<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>An iOS Blog</title><description>This blog talks about iOS development using Swift and methods for life-long learning such as SRS flashcards.</description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 07:05:22 +0700</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 07:05:22 +0700</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://www.anne-hanw.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Simple%20Leitner%20Box</guid><title>Simple Leitner Box</title><description>Digital Scheduler for Physical Flashcards</description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Simple%20Leitner%20Box</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 07:03:55 +0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Leitner Box Scheduler for physical flashcards.</h2><p>This app is based on a 7-levels, 64-days calendar cycle of Leitner System.</p><h3>Why should you use a digital scheduler?</h3><p>Apart from taking a lot of time to prepare a physical schedule, the problem with traditional schedule arises when you forget to review, making you lose the place in the cycle. This app fixes that by showing both due and missed levels.</p><h3>Features:</h3><ul><li>Start freshly from a new schedule</li><li>Continue from your existing schedule (must be based on 7-levels type)</li><li>Automatically calculate levels due each day and which level to do first</li><li>Automatically catch up with levels from missed days</li><li>Simple interface</li><li>No sign-up or sign-in required, your data is synced with your Apple ID</li></ul>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.anne-hanw.com/apps/Simple%20Leitner%20Box</guid><title>Simple Leitner Box</title><description></description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com/apps/Simple%20Leitner%20Box</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 07:03:43 +0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This app was born on a night which I had to prepare for a few heavily memorization-based exams. It is based on the Leitner System. This system was proposed by Sebastian Leitner in the 1970s.</p><p>The idea of this is that in order to remember something, you have to review it at a certain interval, also known as "the forgetting curve". To combat this, Spaced-Repetition methods were invented.</p><p>Today, there are many variations of SRS implementation, integration, and software such as Anki, Rosetta Stone etc.</p><p>This app is based on the simple 7-levels, 64-days cycle schedule. Basically, you prepare a box by putting it in 7 sections (levels). Then you move the cards up or down the levels. Those levels are due on different days depend on the interval. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leitner_system">Learn more about this on Wikipedia.</a></p><p>The problem is that creating a shedule is time consuming, and if you missed a day or forgot to track, you lose the mess up the schedule. That's why this app was made.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.anne-hanw.com/apps/Achievy</guid><title>Achievy</title><description></description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com/apps/Achievy</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 06:49:49 +0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Alternative for physical study planner</h3><p><em>Why this app was made</em></p><p>I wanted to make a study planner that is useful to both students and self-learners.</p><p>Like most students, I have to study a lot of materials for exams. The problem is, many exams have no content scope. This means you have to study <strong>everything</strong> the course provided. This can be very stressful for mainly two reasons. First, you feel anxious because you are not sure if your studying progress is on track. Second, you don't know that you are behind and you discover that too late. This anxiety double itself when you are graded 100% on the final exam, or if you have to take a professional exam that could be a once-in-a-lifetime chance.</p><p>This app focuses on creating a study plan for each material and simply forecast what's the progress will be at the end. The forecast feature has two main benefits. The first one is that you are motivated because you can visualize that every small progress count. Another one is that if you are behind schedule, you see it right away before it's too late.</p><p>As for self-learners, this app provides both flexibility and scope to study. When you want to learn something you're passionate about, you could feel like there are too many materials available on this planet. This app provide a structure to put you on track. Supported types of plans are: tracking amount, tracking chapters (book or video), and tracking comprehension percentage.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Simple%20Leitner%20Box/Credits</guid><title>Credits</title><description></description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Simple%20Leitner%20Box/Credits</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 05:18:00 +0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>App Icon</h2><p>"Leitner System" is a concept proposed by Sebastian Leitner in the 1970s.</p><p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leitner_system">Learn more about this on Wikipedia.</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Simple%20Leitner%20Box/Privacy-Policy</guid><title>Privacy Policy</title><description></description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Simple%20Leitner%20Box/Privacy-Policy</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 05:14:37 +0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Privacy Policy</h2><p>Annicha Hanwilai built the Simple Leitner Box app as a Free app. This SERVICE is provided by Annicha Hanwilai at no cost and is intended for use as is.</p><p>This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.</p><p>If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy. The Personal Information that I collect is used for providing and improving the Service. I will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.</p><p>The terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, which is accessible at Simple Leitner Box unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy.</p><p><strong>Information Collection and Use</strong></p><p>For a better experience, while using our Service, I may require you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information. The information that I request will be retained on your device and is not collected by me in any way.</p><p>The user-generated content will be stored and synced in your CloudKit private container. CloudKit is a product by Apple Inc.</p><p><strong>Log Data</strong></p><p>I want to inform you that whenever you use my Service, in a case of an error in the app I collect data and information (through third party products) on your phone called Log Data. This Log Data may include information such as your device Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, device name, operating system version, the configuration of the app when utilizing my Service, the time and date of your use of the Service, and other statistics.</p><p><strong>Cookies</strong></p><p>Cookies are files with a small amount of data that are commonly used as anonymous unique identifiers. These are sent to your browser from the websites that you visit and are stored on your device's internal memory.</p><p>This Service does not use these “cookies” explicitly. However, the app may use third party code and libraries that use “cookies” to collect information and improve their services. You have the option to either accept or refuse these cookies and know when a cookie is being sent to your device. If you choose to refuse our cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of this Service.</p><p><strong>Service Providers</strong></p><p>I may employ third-party companies and individuals due to the following reasons:</p><ul><li>To facilitate our Service;</li><li>To provide the Service on our behalf;</li><li>To perform Service-related services; or</li><li>To assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.</li></ul><p>I want to inform users of this Service that these third parties have access to your Personal Information. The reason is to perform the tasks assigned to them on our behalf. However, they are obligated not to disclose or use the information for any other purpose.</p><p><strong>Security</strong></p><p>I value your trust in providing us your Personal Information, thus we are striving to use commercially acceptable means of protecting it. But remember that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and reliable, and I cannot guarantee its absolute security.</p><p><strong>Links to Other Sites</strong></p><p>This Service may contain links to other sites. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that site. Note that these external sites are not operated by me. Therefore, I strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of these websites. I have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party sites or services.</p><p><strong>Children’s Privacy</strong></p><p>These Services do not address anyone under the age of 4. I do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. In the case I discover that a child under 4 has provided me with personal information, I immediately delete this from our servers. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with personal information, please contact me so that I will be able to do necessary actions.</p><p><strong>Changes to This Privacy Policy</strong></p><p>I may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.</p><p>This policy is effective as of 2021-09-29</p><p><strong>Contact Us</strong></p><p>If you have any questions or suggestions about my Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact me at anne.hanw@gmail.com.</p><p>This privacy policy page was created at <a href="https://privacypolicytemplate.net">privacypolicytemplate.net</a> and modified/generated by <a href="https://app-privacy-policy-generator.nisrulz.com/">App Privacy Policy Generator</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Simple%20Leitner%20Box/Terms-and-Conditions</guid><title>Terms &amp; Conditions</title><description></description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Simple%20Leitner%20Box/Terms-and-Conditions</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 05:00:46 +0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Terms &amp; Conditions</h2><p>By downloading or using the app, these terms will automatically apply to you – you should make sure therefore that you read them carefully before using the app. You’re not allowed to copy, or modify the app, any part of the app, or our trademarks in any way. You’re not allowed to attempt to extract the source code of the app, and you also shouldn’t try to translate the app into other languages, or make derivative versions. The app itself, and all the trade marks, copyright, database rights and other intellectual property rights related to it, still belong to Annicha Hanwilai.</p><p>Annicha Hanwilai is committed to ensuring that the app is as useful and efficient as possible. For that reason, we reserve the right to make changes to the app or to charge for its services, at any time and for any reason. We will never charge you for the app or its services without making it very clear to you exactly what you’re paying for.</p><p>The Simple Leitner Box app stores and processes personal data that you have provided to us, in order to provide my Service. It’s your responsibility to keep your phone and access to the app secure. We therefore recommend that you do not jailbreak or root your phone, which is the process of removing software restrictions and limitations imposed by the official operating system of your device. It could make your phone vulnerable to malware/viruses/malicious programs, compromise your phone’s security features and it could mean that the Simple Leitner Box app won’t work properly or at all.</p><p>You should be aware that there are certain things that Annicha Hanwilai will not take responsibility for. Certain functions of the app will require the app to have an active internet connection. The connection can be Wi-Fi, or provided by your mobile network provider, but Annicha Hanwilai cannot take responsibility for the app not working at full functionality if you don’t have access to Wi-Fi, and you don’t have any of your data allowance left.</p><p>If you’re using the app outside of an area with Wi-Fi, you should remember that your terms of the agreement with your mobile network provider will still apply. As a result, you may be charged by your mobile provider for the cost of data for the duration of the connection while accessing the app, or other third party charges. In using the app, you’re accepting responsibility for any such charges, including roaming data charges if you use the app outside of your home territory (i.e. region or country) without turning off data roaming. If you are not the bill payer for the device on which you’re using the app, please be aware that we assume that you have received permission from the bill payer for using the app.</p><p>Along the same lines, Annicha Hanwilai cannot always take responsibility for the way you use the app i.e. You need to make sure that your device stays charged – if it runs out of battery and you can’t turn it on to avail the Service, Annicha Hanwilai cannot accept responsibility.</p><p>With respect to Annicha Hanwilai’s responsibility for your use of the app, when you’re using the app, it’s important to bear in mind that although we endeavour to ensure that it is updated and correct at all times, we do rely on third parties to provide information to us so that we can make it available to you. Annicha Hanwilai accepts no liability for any loss, direct or indirect, you experience as a result of relying wholly on this functionality of the app.</p><p>At some point, we may wish to update the app. The app is currently available on iOS – the requirements for system(and for any additional systems we decide to extend the availability of the app to) may change, and you’ll need to download the updates if you want to keep using the app. Annicha Hanwilai does not promise that it will always update the app so that it is relevant to you and/or works with the iOS version that you have installed on your device. However, you promise to always accept updates to the application when offered to you, We may also wish to stop providing the app, and may terminate use of it at any time without giving notice of termination to you. Unless we tell you otherwise, upon any termination, (a) the rights and licenses granted to you in these terms will end; (b) you must stop using the app, and (if needed) delete it from your device.</p><p><strong>Changes to This Terms and Conditions</strong></p><p>I may update our Terms and Conditions from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Terms and Conditions on this page.</p><p>These terms and conditions are effective as of 2021-09-29</p><p><strong>Contact Us</strong></p><p>If you have any questions or suggestions about my Terms and Conditions, do not hesitate to contact me at anne.hanw@gmail.com.</p><p>This Terms and Conditions page was generated by <a href="https://app-privacy-policy-generator.nisrulz.com/">App Privacy Policy Generator</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Achievy</guid><title>Achievy</title><description>Take charge of your studying progress.</description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Achievy</link><pubDate>Wed, 1 Sep 2021 13:41:16 +0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Take charge of your study life, achieve your study goal and feel in control.</h2><p>Achievy suggests the minimum amount to study each day and visualizes what you will achieve on the deadline.</p><h3>Features:</h3><ul><li>Let you create your own material to study - be it your book, online video course, etc.</li><li>Suggests minimum amount to study each day.</li><li>Tells you what the "new" tomorrow amount will be if you don't study today. With this, you have the flexibility to adjust your plan as life happens.</li></ul><h3>Great for:</h3><ul><li>Preparing for exams that require you to study a lot of materials in a limited time.</li><li>Self-study and make sure you are in control of your goal.</li></ul>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Achievy/Credits</guid><title>Credits</title><description></description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Achievy/Credits</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 09:59:14 +0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>App Icon</h2><p>App icon by <a href="https://www.facebook.com/tadnatee.hanwilai">Tadnatee Hanwilai</a></p><h3>Authors of the button icons and images used in this app</h3><p><a href="https://www.flaticon.com/authors/dmitri13">dmitri13 from www.flaticon.com</a></p><p><a href="https://www.flaticon.com/authors/smashicons">smashicons from www.flaticon.com</a></p><p><a href="https://www.flaticon.com/authors/freepik">freepik from www.flaticon.com</a></p><p><a href="https://www.flaticon.com/authors/bogdan-rosu">bogdan-rosu from www.flaticon.com</a></p><p><a href="https://www.flaticon.com/authors/pixel-perfect">Pixel Perfect from www.flaticon.com</a></p><p><a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/U_diPCXCBxU">Aurora: Photo by Johny Goerend from Unsplash</a></p><p><a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/EngLPePzg7U">Lightning: Photo by Luka Vovk from Unsplash</a></p><p><a href="https://unsplash.com/photos/pNLLzCPrXec">Spiral Staircase: Photo by Mika Korhonen from Unsplash</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Achievy/Privacy-Policy</guid><title>Privacy Policy</title><description></description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Achievy/Privacy-Policy</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 09:58:53 +0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Privacy Policy</h2><p>Annicha Hanwilai built the Achievy app as an Ad Supported Freemium app. This SERVICE is provided by Annicha Hanwilai at no cost and is intended for use as is.</p><p>This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.</p><p>If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy. The Personal Information that I collect is used for providing and improving the Service. I will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.</p><p>The terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, which is accessible at Achievy unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy.</p><p><strong>Information Collection and Use</strong></p><p>For a better experience, while using our Service, I may require you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information, including but not limited to Email. The information that I request will be retained on your device and is not collected by me in any way.</p><p>The app does use third party services that may collect information used to identify you.</p><p>Link to privacy policy of third party service providers used by the app</p><ul><li><a href="https://support.google.com/admob/answer/6128543?hl=en">AdMob</a></li><li><a href="https://firebase.google.com/policies/analytics">Google Analytics for Firebase</a></li></ul><p><strong>Log Data</strong></p><p>I want to inform you that whenever you use my Service, in a case of an error in the app I collect data and information (through third party products) on your phone called Log Data. This Log Data may include information such as your device Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, device name, operating system version, the configuration of the app when utilizing my Service, the time and date of your use of the Service, and other statistics.</p><p><strong>Cookies</strong></p><p>Cookies are files with a small amount of data that are commonly used as anonymous unique identifiers. These are sent to your browser from the websites that you visit and are stored on your device's internal memory.</p><p>This Service does not use these “cookies” explicitly. However, the app may use third party code and libraries that use “cookies” to collect information and improve their services. You have the option to either accept or refuse these cookies and know when a cookie is being sent to your device. If you choose to refuse our cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of this Service.</p><p><strong>Service Providers</strong></p><p>I may employ third-party companies and individuals due to the following reasons:</p><ul><li>To facilitate our Service;</li><li>To provide the Service on our behalf;</li><li>To perform Service-related services; or</li><li>To assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.</li></ul><p>I want to inform users of this Service that these third parties have access to your Personal Information. The reason is to perform the tasks assigned to them on our behalf. However, they are obligated not to disclose or use the information for any other purpose.</p><p><strong>Security</strong></p><p>I value your trust in providing us your Personal Information, thus we are striving to use commercially acceptable means of protecting it. But remember that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and reliable, and I cannot guarantee its absolute security.</p><p><strong>Links to Other Sites</strong></p><p>This Service may contain links to other sites. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that site. Note that these external sites are not operated by me. Therefore, I strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of these websites. I have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party sites or services.</p><p><strong>Children’s Privacy</strong></p><p>These Services do not address anyone under the age of 13. I do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. In the case I discover that a child under 13 has provided me with personal information, I immediately delete this from our servers. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with personal information, please contact me so that I will be able to do necessary actions.</p><p><strong>Changes to This Privacy Policy</strong></p><p>I may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.</p><p>This policy is effective as of 2021-08-14</p><p><strong>Contact Us</strong></p><p>If you have any questions or suggestions about my Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact me at anne.hanw@gmail.com.</p><p>This privacy policy page was created at <a href="https://privacypolicytemplate.net">privacypolicytemplate.net</a> and modified/generated by <a href="https://app-privacy-policy-generator.nisrulz.com/">App Privacy Policy Generator</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Achievy/Terms-and-Conditions</guid><title>Terms &amp; Conditions</title><description></description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com/download/Achievy/Terms-and-Conditions</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 09:58:53 +0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2>Terms &amp; Conditions</h2><p>By downloading or using the app, these terms will automatically apply to you – you should make sure therefore that you read them carefully before using the app. You’re not allowed to copy, or modify the app, any part of the app, or our trademarks in any way. You’re not allowed to attempt to extract the source code of the app, and you also shouldn’t try to translate the app into other languages, or make derivative versions. The app itself, and all the trade marks, copyright, database rights and other intellectual property rights related to it, still belong to Annicha Hanwilai.</p><p>Annicha Hanwilai is committed to ensuring that the app is as useful and efficient as possible. For that reason, we reserve the right to make changes to the app or to charge for its services, at any time and for any reason. We will never charge you for the app or its services without making it very clear to you exactly what you’re paying for.</p><p>The Achievy app stores and processes personal data that you have provided to us, in order to provide my Service. It’s your responsibility to keep your phone and access to the app secure. We therefore recommend that you do not jailbreak or root your phone, which is the process of removing software restrictions and limitations imposed by the official operating system of your device. It could make your phone vulnerable to malware/viruses/malicious programs, compromise your phone’s security features and it could mean that the Achievy app won’t work properly or at all.</p><p>The app does use third party services that declare their own Terms and Conditions.</p><p>Link to Terms and Conditions of third party service providers used by the app</p><ul><li><a href="https://developers.google.com/admob/terms">AdMob</a></li><li><a href="https://firebase.google.com/terms/analytics">Google Analytics for Firebase</a></li></ul><p>You should be aware that there are certain things that Annicha Hanwilai will not take responsibility for. Certain functions of the app will require the app to have an active internet connection. The connection can be Wi-Fi, or provided by your mobile network provider, but Annicha Hanwilai cannot take responsibility for the app not working at full functionality if you don’t have access to Wi-Fi, and you don’t have any of your data allowance left.</p><p>If you’re using the app outside of an area with Wi-Fi, you should remember that your terms of the agreement with your mobile network provider will still apply. As a result, you may be charged by your mobile provider for the cost of data for the duration of the connection while accessing the app, or other third party charges. In using the app, you’re accepting responsibility for any such charges, including roaming data charges if you use the app outside of your home territory (i.e. region or country) without turning off data roaming. If you are not the bill payer for the device on which you’re using the app, please be aware that we assume that you have received permission from the bill payer for using the app.</p><p>Along the same lines, Annicha Hanwilai cannot always take responsibility for the way you use the app i.e. You need to make sure that your device stays charged – if it runs out of battery and you can’t turn it on to avail the Service, Annicha Hanwilai cannot accept responsibility.</p><p>With respect to Annicha Hanwilai’s responsibility for your use of the app, when you’re using the app, it’s important to bear in mind that although we endeavour to ensure that it is updated and correct at all times, we do rely on third parties to provide information to us so that we can make it available to you. Annicha Hanwilai accepts no liability for any loss, direct or indirect, you experience as a result of relying wholly on this functionality of the app.</p><p>At some point, we may wish to update the app. The app is currently available on – the requirements for system(and for any additional systems we decide to extend the availability of the app to) may change, and you’ll need to download the updates if you want to keep using the app. Annicha Hanwilai does not promise that it will always update the app so that it is relevant to you and/or works with the version that you have installed on your device. However, you promise to always accept updates to the application when offered to you, We may also wish to stop providing the app, and may terminate use of it at any time without giving notice of termination to you. Unless we tell you otherwise, upon any termination, (a) the rights and licenses granted to you in these terms will end; (b) you must stop using the app, and (if needed) delete it from your device.</p><p><strong>Changes to This Terms and Conditions</strong></p><p>I may update our Terms and Conditions from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Terms and Conditions on this page.</p><p>These terms and conditions are effective as of 2021-08-14</p><p><strong>Contact Us</strong></p><p>If you have any questions or suggestions about my Terms and Conditions, do not hesitate to contact me at anne.hanw@gmail.com.</p><p>This Terms and Conditions page was generated by <a href="https://app-privacy-policy-generator.nisrulz.com/">App Privacy Policy Generator</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.anne-hanw.com/posts/Anki-multiple-choice-card</guid><title>How to create multiple choices question on Anki</title><description>This is a test description</description><link>https://www.anne-hanw.com/posts/Anki-multiple-choice-card</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 16:04:19 +0700</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>How to create multiple choices question on Anki</h1><p>Are you looking for a way to create multiple choices question on Anki?</p><p>This post shows how to do that. After this post, you will be able to create a card like this one.</p><img src="https://www.anne-hanw.com/images/Anki-preview-bacon.png" alt="Bacon card preview"/><p>The answer choices are randomized cloze hint.</p><img src="https://www.anne-hanw.com/images/Anki-editor-bacon.png" alt="Bacon card input preview"/><h3>First, make a copy of cloze type.</h3><p>Firstly, go the the add card editor, press <strong>Type</strong> on the top left.</p><img src="https://www.anne-hanw.com/images/Anki-type-button.png" alt="Type button"/><p>This will bring up a list of note type, then on the bottom left, press <strong>manage</strong>.</p><img src="https://www.anne-hanw.com/images/Anki-choose-note-type.png" alt="Note type list"/><p>This will shows a the same list of existing note types but with buttons on the right. Press <strong>add</strong> to create new type.</p><img src="https://www.anne-hanw.com/images/Anki-note-type-list.png" alt="Manage note types"/><p>This will bring up another list, this list allows you to create a copy of the chosen note type. We are going to copy the Cloze type. Press <strong>Add: Cloze</strong> then press <strong>OK</strong>.</p><img src="https://www.anne-hanw.com/images/Anki-add-note-type.png" alt="Bacon car input preview"/><p>Give the new note type a name.</p><img src="https://www.anne-hanw.com/images/Anki-rename-type.png" alt="Bacon car input preview"/><p>Now, close all the pop ups, go back to the card editor and choose the newly created note type.</p><p>Then, bring up the fields list by pressing <strong>Fields</strong></p><p>Edit it until it so that it looks like this</p><img src="https://www.anne-hanw.com/images/Anki-editor-fields.png" alt="Bacon car input preview"/><h2>Edit the card template.</h2><p>Back to the editor, press the cards button to bring up the template. Edit them to look like this.</p><h3>Front</h3><pre><code>&lt;h2&gt;{{<span class="type">Topic</span>}}&lt;/h2&gt;

<span class="comment">// This is where the text and choices will populate</span>
&lt;div id=<span class="string">"choices"</span> <span class="keyword">class</span>=<span class="string">"choice-holder"</span>&gt;{{cloze:<span class="type">Text</span>}}&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;

<span class="comment">// select cloze element</span>
<span class="keyword">var</span> cloze = document.<span class="call">querySelectorAll</span>(<span class="string">".cloze"</span>);
<span class="keyword">for</span> (<span class="keyword">var</span> i = <span class="number">0</span>; i &lt; cloze.<span class="property">length</span>; i++) {
	<span class="keyword">var</span> hint = cloze[i].innerHTML
	
	<span class="comment">// anki create additional bracket for cloze hint, we want them removed</span>
	<span class="keyword">var</span> newHint = hint.<span class="call">substring</span>(<span class="number">1</span>, hint.<span class="property">length</span> - <span class="number">1</span>)

	cloze[i].textContent = <span class="string">""</span>;

	<span class="keyword">if</span> (newHint != <span class="string">"..."</span>)  {

		<span class="keyword">var</span> list = <span class="string">""</span>
		<span class="comment">// split the choices</span>
		<span class="keyword">var</span> arr = newHint.<span class="call">split</span>(<span class="string">"/"</span>);
	
		<span class="keyword">if</span> (arr.<span class="property">length</span> &gt; <span class="number">1</span>) {
		    <span class="comment">//shuffle the choices</span>
		    <span class="call">shuffle</span>(arr)
		}

		<span class="keyword">for</span> (<span class="keyword">var</span> j = <span class="number">0</span>; j &lt; arr.<span class="property">length</span>; j++) {
			<span class="comment">// uncomment this line if you want the choices to be in separate lines
			//list = list + "&lt;br&gt;"</span>
			list = list + <span class="string">"&lt;span class=box&gt;"</span> + arr[j] + <span class="string">"&lt;/span&gt;"</span>
		}

		<span class="comment">//put back the separated list to the card</span>
		cloze[i].innerHTML = list
	} <span class="keyword">else</span> {
	cloze[i].textContent += <span class="string">"_____ "</span>;
	}
}

function shuffle (array) {
  <span class="keyword">var</span> i = <span class="number">0</span>
	, j = <span class="number">0</span>
	, temp = null

  <span class="keyword">for</span> (i = array.<span class="property">length</span> - <span class="number">1</span>; i &gt; <span class="number">0</span>; i -= <span class="number">1</span>) {
	j = <span class="type">Math</span>.<span class="call">floor</span>(<span class="type">Math</span>.<span class="call">random</span>() * (i + <span class="number">1</span>))
	temp = array[i]
	array[i] = array[j]
	array[j] = temp
  }
}

&lt;/script&gt;
</code></pre><h3>Back</h3><pre><code>&lt;span id=<span class="string">"answer"</span> &gt;{{cloze:<span class="type">Text</span>}}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;span id=<span class="string">"hidden"</span>&gt;{{cloze:<span class="type">Clozed Extra</span>}}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;div id=<span class="string">"note"</span> <span class="keyword">class</span>=<span class="string">"gray"</span>&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;span <span class="keyword">class</span>=<span class="string">"gray"</span>&gt;&lt;br&gt;{{<span class="type">Extra</span>}}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
<span class="keyword">var</span> holder = document.<span class="call">getElementById</span>(<span class="string">"note"</span>);
<span class="keyword">var</span> hiddenContent = null
hiddenContent = document.<span class="call">getElementById</span>(<span class="string">"hidden"</span>);

<span class="keyword">if</span> (hiddenContent != <span class="string">""</span>) {
	<span class="keyword">var</span> hiddenNote = document.<span class="call">querySelectorAll</span>(<span class="string">"#hidden .cloze"</span>);
	<span class="keyword">if</span> (hiddenNote[<span class="number">0</span>] != null) {
			holder.<span class="property">innerHTML</span> = hiddenNote[<span class="number">0</span>].innerHTML
	}
	
}

&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;script&gt;

<span class="keyword">var</span> clozes = document.<span class="call">querySelectorAll</span>(<span class="string">"#answer .cloze"</span>);
<span class="comment">//document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML = "hello";</span>

<span class="keyword">for</span> (<span class="keyword">var</span> i = <span class="number">0</span>; i &lt; clozes.<span class="property">length</span>; i++) {
	<span class="keyword">var</span> temp = clozes[i].innerHTML;
	clozes[i].innerHTML =  '&lt;span <span class="keyword">class</span>=<span class="string">"box green"</span>&gt;' + temp + <span class="string">"&lt;/span&gt;"</span>
}


&lt;/script&gt;
</code></pre><h3>Style</h3><pre><code>.<span class="call">card</span> {
 font-family: arial;
 font-size: 20px;
 text-align: left;
 color: black;
 background-color: white;
}

<span class="call">img</span> {
	max-height: 140px
}

.<span class="call">hide</span> {
	visibility: hidden;
	font-size: 0px;
}

.<span class="property">hide</span> img{
	max-width: 0px;
}

.<span class="call">cloze</span> {
 font-weight: bold;
 color: brown;
  visibility: visible;
}


.<span class="call">box</span> {
  color: brown;
  display: inline-block;
  border-radius: <span class="number">1</span>.5em;
  padding: 4px 8px;
  border: solid 2px;
  margin: 5px;
  border-color: brown;
  background: pink;
	margin: <span class="number">1</span>.5px;
}

#hidden {
	display: none;
}

 .<span class="call">gray</span> {
	color: gray;
}

.<span class="call">green</span> {
	color: green;
	border-color: green;
	background-color: lightyellow;
}

</code></pre>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>